Guide to the The Patty Mucha Papers MSS.342
Fales Library and Special Collections
Patty Mucha Papers
1936-2022
1969-1979
Fales Library and Special Collections
Mucha, Pat
MSS.342
16.50 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 7 manuscript boxes, 5 small flat boxes, 6 oversize flat boxes, and 2 small card boxes
Patty Mucha (Patricia Muschinski) was born in Milwaukee, Wisconsin on June 26, 1935. She and Claes Oldenburg were married in 1960 and divorced in 1970. Mucha appeared in Oldenburg films made by Rudy Wurlitzer and Robert Breer, as well as in films by Jean Dupuy, Rudy Burckhardt, Andy Warhol and Red Grooms. She also participated in the Happenings of Jim Dine, Robert Whitman, Dick Higgins, Alex Hay, Steve Paxton, Simone Forti, and Sally Gross. The Patty Mucha Papers include artwork, correspondence, ephemera, and manuscripts from artists, poets, dancers, and performers active in the New York City art world during the Pop Art, Happenings, E.A.T., Yippies, and Punk Movements in the 1960s and 1970s.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Patty Mucha Papers were acquired from a dealer in 2012. Accretions to the collection were donated by Mucha in January of 2017 and August 2022; the accession number associated with these addition are 2017.016 and 2023.017.
Arrangement
This material was arranged by Mucha and her original order has been retained.
Series I: Journals include Mucha's personal writing, which is organized chronologically.
Series II: Manuscripts include Mucha's professional writing, which is organized alphabetically by project title.
Series III: Subject Files contains artwork, clippings, collectibles, commercial audiovisual media, correspondence, and photography documenting the life and work of other artists, and is organized alphabetically by artist's name or subject.
Series IV: Media contains 16mm and Super 8mm footage, one complete film, related out-takes and soundtrack material, and assorted home movies. Material is organized by content and retains donor's original order at the box level.
Series V: Photographs contains prints, contact sheets, and negatives. Material is organized by subject and type.
Series VI: 2017 Accretion contains additional materials donated in 2017. These materials have not been arranged by an archivist.
Series VII: 2023 Accretion contains additional materials donated in 2023. These materials have not been arranged by an archivist.
Biographical Note
Patty Mucha (Patricia Muschinski) was born in Milwaukee, Wisconsin on June 26, 1935. She attended Wisconsin State Teachers College in Milwaukee (now the University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee), where she majored in art. Patty first saw Claes Oldenburg while she was at the Oxbow Summer School of Painting and later went to visit him in his Chicago studio. In 1957, she moved to New York to become an artist and met Oldenburg by accident after being there for two months. At the time he was painting portraits, and Mucha became one of his nude models. The last painting that Oldenburg claims to have painted is of Mucha and is titled "Girl with Fur Piece, Portrait of Pat." She and Oldenburg were married in 1960 and divorced in 1970.
Patty Mucha was not only Oldenburg's muse for his main performance ensemble but collaborator for all of his early sewn sculptures. Her contribution to the invention of soft sculpture was the result of the immediate demand for Oldenburg's first exhibition at the Green Gallery in 1962. She appeared in his Ray Gun Theater, which they produced in 1962, and collaborated in sewing costumes and constructing objects and sets for his Happenings and installations. She appeared in Oldenburg films made by Rudy Wurlitzer and Robert Breer as well as in films by Jean Dupuy, Rudy Burckhardt, Andy Warhol and Red Grooms. She also participated in the Happenings of Jim Dine, Robert Whitman, Dick Higgins, Alex Hay, Steve Paxton, Simone Forti, and Sally Gross.
Patty Mucha farms, writes and paints near St. Johnsbury, Vermont. Her essential role in the Pop Art and Happenings scenes is revealed in her as-yet-unpublished memoir, Clean Slate: My Life in the 1960's New York Art World, which in 2022, the title was changed to Threads. Portions of the book have appeared in Art in America as well as in the catalog "Seductive Subversion: Women Pop Artists, 1958–1968." Her poetry books include Poems Traveling, 1971-1973 (Panorama, 1973) and See Vermont: Poems, 1974-1978 (Poets Mimeo Cooperative, 1979).
Biographical information provided by Granary Books with (granarybooks.com) adaptations from Billy Klüver and Julie Martin's entry on Patty Mucha in Jill Berk Jiminez's edition of Dictionary of Artists' Models (Routledge, 2001).
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The Patty Mucha Papers include artwork, correspondence, ephemera, and manuscripts from artists, poets, dancers, and performers active in the New York City art world during the Pop Art, Happenings, E.A.T., Yippies, and Punk Movements in the 1960s and 1970s. In addition, this collection contains Mucha's poetry and communication with artists including Olga Adorno, David Bradshaw, Joe Brainard, Gregory Corso, Jean Dupuy, Bob Dylan, Kenward Elmslie, Deborah Hay, Richard Hell, Jasper Johns, Ray Johnson, Ruth Kligman, Billy Klüver, Frosty Myers, Claes Oldenburg, Robert Rauschenberg, Clarice Rivers, Larry Rivers, Lucas Samaras, Carolee Schneemann and Andy Warhol.
Artists and community -- United States; Diaries; Clippings (information artifacts); Personal correspondence.; Performance art -- New York (State) -- New York -- Exhibitions.; Art objects -- Collectors and collecting.; Artistic collaboration; Women artists -- United States.; Fluxus (Group of artists); American poetry -- 20th century -- History and criticism.; Politics in art.; Photographs.; Typescripts; Memoirs; Schneemann, Carolee, 1939-2019; Hay, Deborah, 1941-; Kligman, Ruth; Elmslie, Kenward; Johnson, Ray, 1927-1995; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997; Dupuy, Jean, 1925-2012; Giorno, John; Johns, Jasper, 1930-; Rivers, Larry, 1925-2002; Brainard, Joe, 1942-1994; Corso, Gregory; Oldenburg, Claes, 1929-2022; Dylan, Bob, 1941-; Warhol, Andy, 1928-1987; Adorno, Olga; Hell, Richard; Rauschenberg, Robert, 1925-2008; Lichtenstein, Dorothy; Padgett, Ron, 1942-
- Series I: Journals
  Arrangement
  Series I: Journals consists of Mucha's personal writing, which is organized chronologically.
  - "Sweden + London (Mostly Dreams)" [Black Notebook], 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Stockholm Dream Book #2" [Black Notebook], 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1967 Yearbook [Brown Calendar Book] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [Blue Memo Book], 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Amagansette Springs Richard + Me" [Black Record Book], 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Y.I.P. Notebook 1972" [Orange Rhodia Notebook] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Y.I.P. Notebook 1972" [Orange Rhodia Notebook] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "See Vermont or Apple Sauce '74" [Monkey Ring Notebook], 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Dowsing 'Higher Consciousness' Workshop, Dr. Wayne London" [Loose Notepad Pages], undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Notes Relating to Kenward's 'Orchid Stories' " [Loose Notebad Pages], undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Re: Poems Traveling" [Loose Notepad Pages], undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Spiritual Stuff" [Loose Notepad Pages], undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: Manuscripts
  Series II: Manuscripts include Mucha's professional writing, which is organized alphabetically by project title.
  - "Children's Story Drafts", undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Complaint /Inquiry Letters", 1972 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - [Contracts, Sales], 1971 - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Fake Interview", undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Little Poems Draft", undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "New Wilderness Audiographics" [Audiocassette, Contact Sheet], 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    General
    This file preserves an original audio element. An access copy of this content may not be available, please ask a Fales archivist.
  - [Photographs of Patty Mucha], 1971, 1979, 1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Poems Traveling Statement", undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Poems Traveling Drafts" [1 of 2], undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Poems Traveling Drafts" [2 of 2], undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Poems Traveling by Patty Oldenburg, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Poems Traveling: Receipts / Thank You Notes", 1974 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Polish Music Performance", circa 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts", Christmas 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1967" [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1967" [2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1968" (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1969" (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1970 - 1971" (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1976" (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1978" (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1979" (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1980" (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1981" (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1982" (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - 1985" (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - Undated" [1 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - Undated" [2 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - Undated" [3 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - Postcard Series ", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - Clarice Poems", undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts: Workshop with Bill Berkson's Comments", 1967 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - Plays", undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts: Forgiveness Poem for Claes", undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - Fragments" [1 of 2], Fall 1970 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "Poetry / Prose Drafts - Fragments" [2 of 2], undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "Publicity / Flyers - Arts Related", 1988 - 2009 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Publicity / Flyers - Writing / Music Related", 1977 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "Seductive Subversion: Women Pop Artists, 1958 - 1968", undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Format: DVD
    Access granted for research viewing.
  - "See Vermont Drafts" [1 of 2], undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "See Vermont Drafts" [2 of 2], undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - See Vermont: Special Edition #9 by Patty Oldenburg, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - "Songs (Words + Music) Drafts", 1980 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - "Vintage Dreams", 1956 - 2011 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Series III: Subject Files
  Series III: Subject Files contains artwork, clippings, collectables, commercial media, correspondence, and photography documenting the life and work of other artists, and is organized alphabetically by artist's name or subject.
  - Alvarez, Maria, 1972, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Artschwager, Richard, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Ashley, Mary L., undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Atkinson, Brendan + Janet, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Atlanta Public Library, 3/8/82 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Avedon, Richard, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Aylon, Helène, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Baker, Betsy: Art in America [1 of 2], 2000 - 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baker, Betsy: Art in America [2 of 2], 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Baracks, Barbara, 1974, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Barr, Victoria, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bellamy, Miles, 2000 - 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bellamy, Richard (Dick), 1980 - 1985, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Berkson, Bill, 1974, 1975, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bourdon, David, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bradshaw, David: Correspondence, 1972 - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bradshaw, David: "Small Art Pieces", 1988, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brakhage, Stan, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brainard, Joe: [Christmas Card Collage], Christmas 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Breer, Robert: Correspondence, 2001 - 2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Breer, Robert: Flix, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brodey, Jim, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Brown, Rebecca, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Burton, Scott, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Cage, John: Pop Festival Ticket, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Carrol, Paul: Follett Publishing Company, Big Table Books, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Christo + Jeanne-Claude, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Copley, Noma, 10/14/1970 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Corbett, Bill, 1996, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Corso, Gregory, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Craven, Jay, 1973 - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Creeley, Robert, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Davis, Bevan + Michelle, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Denney, Alice, 2000 - 2010 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Deacon, Richard, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - De Kooning, Willem: Thomas Ammann Fine Art Ag Zurich, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - De Maria, Walter, 1967 - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Dine, Nancy, 1993 - 1996 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Di Palma, Ray, 1974, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Dix, Byron E., 1982 - 1983 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Dupuy, Jean, 1974 - 1984, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Dupuy / Adorno / Klüver, Olga: Correspondence 1970 - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Dupuy / Adorno / Klüver, Olga: Correspondence 1980 - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Dupuy / Adorno / Klüver, Olga: Correspondence 1990 - 1999 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Dupuy / Adorno / Klüver, Olga: Correspondence 2001 - 2008 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Dupuy / Adorno / Klüver, Olga: Correspondence - Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Dupuy / Adorno / Klüver, Olga: Correspondence - Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Dupuy / Adorno / Klüver, Olga: Correspondence - Kids, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Dylan, Bob: Clippings, 1980, 1997, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Dylan, Bob: "Drafts / Manuscripts to Dylan from Mucha", 1971 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Dylan, Bob: [Letter from Dylan to Mucha], undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Early, Marcia, circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "Ed from Corfu", January 20 [no year] (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Edelheidt, Martha, 1974, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Edwards, Karen: Correspondence [1 of 4], 1972 - 1981 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Edwards, Karen: Correspondence [2 of 4], 1971 - 1980, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Edwards, Karen: Correspondence [3 of 4], 1971 - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Edwards, Karen: Correspondence [4 of 4], 1975 - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Eisenhauer, Lettie Lou, 1968, 1972, 2002, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Elmslie, Kenward: Correspondence, various (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Elmslie, Kenward: Postcards, various (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Ervin, Terrence, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Ettenberg, Frank, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Fahlström, Öyvind, 1972, 1974, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Felson, Sid, November 3, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Fisher, Joel, 1971, 1975, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Forti, Simone, 1996 - 2004 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Frascone, Angela, 1975 - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Friefield, Larry, August 5, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Gilman, Peter, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, 1973, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Giorno, John, various (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Gitlin, Maria, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Godfrey, John, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Goldberg, Mike, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Gonzales, Manuel, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Gray, Darrel, 1974 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Greenberg, Harry, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Grofsky, Maxine, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Gross, Mimi, 2003 - 2006 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Gross, Sally, 1993, 1995, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Guerilla Art Action Group, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Gutman, Walter, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Hartman, Yuki, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Harvey, Emily, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Haseloff, Charles, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Hay, Deborah, various (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Hell, Richard: Correspondence 1969 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Hell, Richard: Correspondence 1970 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Hell, Richard: Correspondence 1971 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Hell, Richard: Correspondence 1972 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Hell, Richard: Correspondence 1973 - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Hell, Richard: Correspondence 1981 - 2005 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hell, Richard: Correspondence [no date], undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hell, Richard: Clippings, Postcards, Memorabilia, various (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hell, Richard: Emails, 2002 - 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hell, Richard: Memoir Excerpts, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hell, Richard: "Patty's Christmas Card: Image of a Magic Argument", Christmas 1969 (Box 5, Object ID: 342.2.0001)
  - Hell, Richard: Poems + Drawings, various (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hell, Richard: Postcards, various (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hell, Richard: "Richard's Girlfriends" [Correspondence], 1978, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hendricks, Geoff, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Hendricks, Jon, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Henri - Ford, Charles, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hickman, Annie, 1999, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hickman, Anne: Marilyn Monroe, 1971 (Box 5, Object ID: 342.2.0006)
  - Higgins, Dick, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Hoffman, Abbie: Clippings, 1972, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Hollo, Anslem, May 9, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Holman, Bob, 1978 - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Houlberg, Barbara, various (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hoyen, Andrew, August 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Huang, Al Chung, 1994 - 1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Hulten, Pontus, 1973, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Irvine, Chippy, various (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Janis Gallery, 1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Jarvis, Barbara, 1994 - 1997 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Johns, Jasper, 1969, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Johnson, Ray, 1971, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Johnston, Jill, 1999 - 2011 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Joseph, Branden: "No More Apologies: Pop Art + Pop Music", undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Kaprow, Allan, 1961, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Kim, Ann, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Kligman, Ruth, 1974 - 1976 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Klüver, Maya, 1974, 1981, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Klüver, William + Julie Martin, various (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Knott, Bill, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Kogelnik, Kiki, 1989 - 1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Kohloff, Ralph, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - König, Kasper, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Kopelman, Rudolph, circa 1976 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard, May 5, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Kron, Joan + Audrey Sabol, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Krauss, Ruth, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Langley, Michael, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Laughlin, James, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Lederer, Bill, 1983, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Lerner, Michael, circa 1969 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Levine, Les: Museum of Mott Art, Inc., 1974, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Lichtenstein, Roy: [Exhibition Advertisements], 1994, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Lippard, Lucy, June 1972 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Lobel, Michael, 2004 - 2005, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Malanga, Gerard, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Manupelli, George, 2000, 2006, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Martin, Tandy, 1977, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Masters, Greg, 1980, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Mathews, Harry, July 7, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Mattingly, George: Blue Wind Press, April 14, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Mayer, Bernadette, May 1, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - McElroy, Bob, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Mikolowski, Ken + Ann: The Alternative Press, June 18, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Milwaukee Art Museum, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, various (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: New York, various (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: Poets, Writers, various (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Morris, Robert, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Morrow, Charlie: New Wilderness Foundation, Inc., 1980 - 1982 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Morton, Jay, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Mucha, Patty: California Driver License, June 28, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Mucha, Patty: Photo Snow Globe, undated (Box 5, Object ID: 342.2.0002)
  - Murphy, Duncan, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Nakhova, Irina, 1992 - 1993 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Neugroschel, Joachim, 1968, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Nomland, John B., undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Obama, Barack, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Ogden, Don, 1980 - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Öhrner, Annika, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Oldenburg, Claes: Articles, various (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Oldenburg, Claes: Correspondence 1968 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Oldenburg, Claes: Correspondence 1970 - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Oldenburg, Claes: Correspondence 1990 - 2011 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Oldenburg, Claes: Events, various (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Oldenburg, Claes: Postcards, 1968 - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Oldenburg, Claes: Ray Gun Theater, 1962 - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Oldenburg, Claes: Youth International Party (Y.I.P.) Sketch, undated (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Oldenburg, Gösta + Elsie, 1968 - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Oldenburg, Lisa, 1992 - 1998 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Oldenburg, Richard + Mel, 1993, 2004 - 2005 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Östlin, Barbro, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Owen, Maureen, 1977 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Padgett, Ron, 1978, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Paris Review (Fayette), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Paxton, Steve, 1971, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Phaidon Press: Jamie James' Pop Art, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Picard, Lil, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Pizer, John, undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Poets Mimeo Co-Op, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Press, David: Jazz Gallery, 1980 - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Rainer, Yvonne, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert: Clippings + Correspondence, various (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert: Happy New Year Image, February 9, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert: A Memorial, Metropolitan Museum of Art [Invitation], October 27, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert: A Memorial, Museum of Modern Art [Invitation], October 26, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert: Merry Xmas Photograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Rhuynhart, Sue, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Rivers, Clarice: Correspondence, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Rivers, Clarice: Postcards, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Rivers, Larry, 1975 - 1977, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Rockburne, Dorothea, 1971, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Roos, Tonie, 1972 - 2009 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Rosenquist, James: The Big Paintings, 30 Years with Leo Castelli [Advertisement], October 15th [no year] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rubin, Jerry, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Samaras, Lucas, 1970, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sanders, Ed, October 4, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Saroff, Raymond, 1989 - 2009 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Saturday Press: Charlotte Mandel, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - See Vermont: Rubber Stamp, undated (Box 5, Object ID: 342.2.0003)
  - Schiff, Harris, October 21, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Schlicter, Joe, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Schneemann, Carolee, 1970, 1974, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Shameless Hussy Press, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Shields, Alan, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Jack: "Sacred Landlordism of Lucky Paradise" [Flyer], 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - St. Johnsbury Television Co-Op, 1979 - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Springs, L.I., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)